<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ekynoxe - Web development in London</title>
        <description>Mathieu Davy's one man web studio</description>
        <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://ww.ekynoxe.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 21:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 21:44:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Migrating comments and the quest for a lightweight solution</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;When I &lt;a href=&quot;/on-jekyll/&quot;&gt;migrated to jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, I also wanted to migrate all my comments. My site doesn&amp;rsquo;t have that many of them, so I thought it should have been a doddle to do it, and I was initially firmly set on using &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed simple, the embedded code interface didn&amp;rsquo;t look too bad within my new website&amp;rsquo;s design, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t care that much about the fact that it works only with javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-18-migrating-comments-and-the-quest-for-a-lightweight-solution/comment.png&quot; alt=&quot;comments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Exporting my comments from Wordpress was very easy through WXR export file, and uploading them to Disqus was equally easy in the first instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t just moving my comments from Wordpress to Disqus under the same domain, but also changing said domain. And that&amp;rsquo;s where the shine started to fade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a domain migration tool provided by Disqus, but no matter how much I tried to migrate comments to the new URLs, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it work.
Maybe I misunderstood something about the process, but the lack of feedback when creating a URL migration and the lack of documentation around the process is appalling at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic Disqus interface is probably OK as long as you stay in the confines of the bog-standard pathway, but for anything else, I found it to be very confusing. Very poor instructions, complete lack of feedback, and zero other on-line resources. The experience wasn&amp;rsquo;t great. I even tried to contact their &amp;ldquo;customer support&amp;rdquo; a few times, but there again I didn&amp;rsquo;t receive even the acknowledgement that my request had been received. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t received anything to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 5 days of experimentation, I tried to migrate the comments to domains on my local machine with a host file entry and on a real, live, website under a development domain of mine, just in case Disqus' back-end needed to verify that this domain worked somehow. I repeated the whole import / migration a few times, but nothing at all was indicating that I was going in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a speck of light on anything was visible. So I&amp;rsquo;ve giving up on Disqus. If you&amp;rsquo;re the standard user, you might be OK. If you have other needs: buzz off&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a look at a few other systems like &lt;a href=&quot;https://moot.it/&quot;&gt;Moot.it&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.livefyre.com/&quot;&gt;Livefyre&lt;/a&gt;, and some others, but they either are too complex and expensive for what I need, or have no obvious support to import anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the waste of time, I have therefore pulled the plug entirely on using any existing third party commenting system at the moment. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve even come around to refusing to give the data of my website to a third party at all anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In time, I&amp;rsquo;ll create my very own commenting system, keeping ownership of my comments, and hopefully share that code with everyone for a self hosted solution that one can control entirely. It may be seen as reinventing the wheel, but I&amp;rsquo;ll disagree. I won&amp;rsquo;t create another Disqus, I&amp;rsquo;ll create a solution for geeks who don&amp;rsquo;t mind looking at a little bit of code, but mind a lot about where their content goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic requirements are pretty simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A secure API for sending/fetching comments. No need for the posting side of things to even work through an interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An administration interface to manage comments, edit, delete, spam them etc&amp;hellip; (I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself doing it all command line!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comment reply notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must be always on: no &amp;ldquo;Heroku 5 seconds spin up of death scenario&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration options per post/page to accept/block or enable/disable comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spam detection will be a must, and probably the trickiest one. But since a self hosted WP installation does it, there must be a way to replicate this with an Akismet key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Things I don&amp;rsquo;t need or care for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avatars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussions. I want this solution to be just comments, and replies to comments. Other systems do discussions, and I&amp;rsquo;ll happily leave it to them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fancy mark-up. Everything will start by being stored as escaped HTML. Then it will be up to clients to use the correct parsers/highlighters. Whether they are JavaScript or ruby, I won&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, you can send me an email with your comments, and I&amp;rsquo;ll add them to the statically hosted ones on this site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 21:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/migrating-comments-and-the-quest-for-a-lightweight-solution</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/migrating-comments-and-the-quest-for-a-lightweight-solution</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>301 redirect your Wordpress website to Jekyll</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re migrating a Wordpress install to Jekyll, and changing your URLs structure at the same time, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to generate redirects for your old URLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-05-301-redirect-your-wordpress-website-to-jekyll/301.png&quot; alt=&quot;301 permanent redirect&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a plugin that does that for you: give it the source and destination domains, and when you generate your Jekyll website, it creates a file pre-formatted with all you need to migrate your old URLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply drop the result in the .htaccess of an Apache install and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, this plugin only supports one source URL scheme, and one destination scheme:
The source URLs must be formatted as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;olddomain&gt;/year/month/day/post-slug&lt;/strong&gt;, while the destination will be&lt;strong&gt;&lt;newdomain&gt;/post-slug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The configuration options are directly inside the code and speak for themselves. You might not need to set a value at all for the source domain, but it&amp;rsquo;s there if you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@@sourceDomain = &quot;&quot;
@@targetDomain = &quot;http://www.ekynoxe.com&quot;
@@RedirectsFileName = &quot;htaccess_redirects&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a sample of what it generated for my own site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...
RedirectMath 301 /2010/08/09/mastermind/? http://www.ekynoxe.com/mastermind/
RedirectMath 301 /2010/09/01/what-really-motivates-us/? http://www.ekynoxe.com/what-really-motivates-us/
RedirectMath 301 /2010/09/06/extending-contact-form-7/? http://www.ekynoxe.com/extending-contact-form-7/
RedirectMath 301 /2010/09/12/create-a-deep-space-background-in-photoshop/? http://www.ekynoxe.com/create-a-deep-space-background-in-photoshop/
RedirectMath 301 /2010/10/24/this-is-it/? http://www.ekynoxe.com/this-is-it/
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The source code is on Github in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ekynoxe/JekyllRedirectsGenerator&quot;&gt;Jekyll 301 Redirects Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer copy / paste, here it is too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# encoding: utf-8
#
# Jekyll 301 Redirects Generator plugin for Wordpress site migration
# http://www.ekynoxe.com/
# Version: 0.0.1 (2014-03-04)
#
# Copyright (c) 2014 Mathieu Davy - ekynoxe - http://ekynoxe.com/
# Licensed under the MIT license
# (http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php)
#
# This plugin creates a list of 301 redirects from old Wordpress urls to new ones.
# It currently only supports one source url structure
#   and one target structure:
#
#   source:    &lt;olddomain&gt;/year/month/day/postname
#
#   target:    &lt;newdomain&gt;/postname
#
module Jekyll

    # Sub-class Jekyll::StaticFile to allow recovery from unimportant exception
    #   when writing the redirects file.
    # I don't like this but that seems to be the only way to get around Jekyll
    #   StaticFile class using &quot;cp&quot; instead of &quot;rename&quot;
    # Found on the SiteMap Generator at
    #   https://github.com/recurser/jekyll-plugins/blob/master/generate_sitemap.rb
    class RedirectsFile &lt; StaticFile
        def write(dest)
            super(dest) rescue ArgumentError
            true
        end
    end

    class RedirectsGenerator &lt; Generator
        safe true
        priority :low

        @@sourceDomain = &quot;&quot;
        @@targetDomain = &quot;http://www.ekynoxe.com&quot;
        @@RedirectsFileName = &quot;htaccess_redirects&quot;

        def generate(site)
            mappedUrls = []

            site.posts.each do |post|
                post_name = post.name.gsub(/\.md$/, &quot;&quot;)
                url_parts = post_name.match(/([0-9]{4})-([0-9]{2})-([0-9]{2})-(.+)/i)

                mappedUrls &lt;&lt; &quot;RedirectMath 301 &quot; + File.join(@@sourceDomain, url_parts[1], url_parts[2], url_parts[3], url_parts[4]) + &quot;/? &quot; + File.join(@@targetDomain, url_parts[4]) + &quot;/&quot;
            end

            site_folder = site.config['destination']
            unless File.directory?(site_folder)
                p = Pathname.new(site_folder)
                p.mkdir
            end

            File.open(File.join( site_folder, @@RedirectsFileName ), 'w') do |f|
                mappedUrls.each do |line|
                    f.write line + &quot;\n&quot;
                end

                f.close
            end

            site.static_files &lt;&lt; Jekyll::RedirectsFile.new(site, site.dest, '/', @@RedirectsFileName)
        end
    end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 21:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/301-redirect-your-wordpress-website-to-jekyll</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/301-redirect-your-wordpress-website-to-jekyll</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>On Jekyll</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! At long last, I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated my personal sites away from Wordpress. My blog and websites have been in need of a design overhaul for a long time, and as I was growing tired of the incessant and ever larger updates required by Wordpress and its plugins, I decided to switch to a static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exit Wordpress, enters Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-02-on-jekyll/wp_to_jkl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wordpress to Jekyll&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For too many years, this migration and redesign has been put on the back burner because of client&amp;rsquo;s work, or heavy training for my &amp;ldquo;little hobby&amp;rdquo;: triathlon. I managed to find a little time here and there over the last year to make some way on a new design, but it&amp;rsquo;s only in the last few months that I really gave it a good push. With a few HTML templates and a clean CSS all ready, I only had to dig into Jekyll and start the migration process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why leave Wordpress?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still remember the first version I used. Wordpress was a super small and very fast CMS to quickly publish posts with some image attachments. It was fast to use, easy to install on any LAMP stack, and fairly easy to maintain. That was before bloat arrived. In the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with too many core upgrades, not just for my site, but also for the others I manage, and frankly, it&amp;rsquo;s been a pain every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; If you have a simple hosted blog on wordpress.com, chances are you don&amp;rsquo;t see any of this, but custom websites on WP can be a real pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; So, I was tired of fortnightly &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo; upgrades where I had to re-upload almost a full website every time, and then go through the pain of checking that every plugin still worked happily with its neighbour and the new core code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Wordpress has its use and it&amp;rsquo;s probably serving millions very well. Not me. Not any-more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted a completely clean slate for my new site. Not another Wordpress theme migration whilst trying to find why a core method has been magically deprecated and that its replacement signature isn&amp;rsquo;t the same. I was going for a new design, a new structure, and more importantly, a new &lt;em&gt;content&lt;/em&gt; structure. So starting from scratch was the best option to have a clean site on all fronts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, I simply wanted to learn Jekyll. It promised to fulfil every one of my geek developer fantasies of being in control of everything, and all from the command line. I could finally go nuts on my &amp;ldquo;own&amp;rdquo; platform without having to reinvent the wheel from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would also be a good opportunity to dig into some open source projects and maybe create and share some useful plugins of my own. This is what I did and some posts will come at a later date detailing my own plugins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to see if I could increase the little SEO juice I&amp;rsquo;m getting by adopting a cleaner and simpler URL structure, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t see myself moving all this within a single Wordpress install without a lot of pain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Blank slate and big expectations, then. Much like a brand new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What is Jekyll?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a static website generator. For those of you who still wonder what that means, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy: from a set of common files on your computer, jekyll will assemble a full website in plain html files. No PHP, no &amp;ldquo;request-time assembly&amp;rdquo;, no server logic. At all! Once written, the files aren&amp;rsquo;t changed by the server, and what clients request are only those files. That also means no database, and no dynamic code! Aside from the simplicity of the hosting setup, it most importantly means that you can completely do away with having them available in the first place, even in your local environment. All you need is a web server that dishes out plain HTML files, and that&amp;rsquo;s all.
It also means a much faster website to serve to your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear you say: &amp;ldquo;But without a database or dynamic code, all in static files, that sounds a bit like a step back, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be right for certain purposes, but in my context of a simple website, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need any dynamic code or a even a database. Actually, my content never needed this, and probably a lot of websites out there simply don&amp;rsquo;t need a database either. For most, it&amp;rsquo;s just a convenient way to store data, but there&amp;rsquo;s absolutely no need for it if you have something like Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer and have written a few web pages, then think about that time all the way back when YOU started web development. If you are a total web developer novice, or even better, if you&amp;rsquo;d try to teach web development to someone new to it: how did / would you start? Probably with a basic html file. You&amp;rsquo;d probably write a few by hand, put them all into a directory, maybe upload them to the FTP server of a basic web host, and you&amp;rsquo;d have your first website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, that&amp;rsquo;s what Jekyll creates for you: it creates &lt;strong&gt;static&lt;/strong&gt; files like you&amp;rsquo;d do by hand. And by automating the generation process, it simplifies the whole thing a fair bit. But that&amp;rsquo;s the easy part of the story. Writing and hosting content for a site generated by Jekyll is dead easy, but unsurprisingly, there&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a journey to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Configuration / personalisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you write or deploy your website, there&amp;rsquo;s an absolute nerd part, which is the preparation of your &amp;ldquo;developer&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;author&amp;rdquo; environment, its configuration, and the plugins you may need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;tons&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/building-static-sites-with-jekyll--net-22211&quot;&gt;on-line&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daveperrett.com/articles/2010/10/12/static-blogging-the-jekyll-way/&quot;&gt;guides for Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and reports of how others did it, which has been a great help, but the very one thing that you&amp;rsquo;ll need if you want to get started easily, is to fork someone&amp;rsquo;s Jekyll repository. That way you will have something that works straight away and that you can start hacking around to make your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started mine from &lt;a href=&quot;http://nefariousdesigns.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Tim&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nefarioustim/kitchen&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;kitchen&amp;rdquo; project&lt;/a&gt;, and the configuration+Rakefile already in there was a godsend to quickly get to speed. I have since added a lot to it and made it mine, but some utilities like the Rakefile haven&amp;rsquo;t changed much. You can also find &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ekynoxe/ekynoxe.com&quot;&gt;the source of this very website on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a migration guide, you can do like I did: follow the excellent one &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulstamatiou.com/how-to-wordpress-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;written by Paul Stamatiou&lt;/a&gt; and discard what you don&amp;rsquo;t need. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a special host other than Github pages, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even look at the Apache stuff, and although my images are on S3+Cloudfront, I haven&amp;rsquo;t gone around automating the deployment process yet. The same goes for comments (more on that further), or special posts types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great thing about Jekyll is that it can be as simple or as complex as you want. As Paul mentions, beware of generation time for large sites, but do apply your own sauce to what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to go to ultra-basics, then the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll website&lt;/a&gt; itself will give you some information. But trust me, after spending hours trying to figure out how plugins or other configuration parameters work, you&amp;rsquo;re much better of looking a code!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;My own setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the goals of getting rid of Wordpress for my own site had always been to get rid of my hosting package. Even if you can host a Wordpress install for free on excellent cloud platforms like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openshift.com/&quot;&gt;openshift&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heroku.com/&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, you will still have to maintain your platform more or less completely, or jump through some hoops to host a static pages website on a host that&amp;rsquo;s not really intended for it. With Jekyll, I decided to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github pages&lt;/a&gt; for hosting, as recommended by many. All you have to do is push either the source of your Jekyll website or the generated static site to a special Github repository on your account, and it gets automatically deployed for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow the first solution (e.g. you don&amp;rsquo;t generate your website &amp;ldquo;locally&amp;rdquo; on your local home machine), there is one thing that Github doesn&amp;rsquo;t do well: custom plugins. Obviously, for security reasons and to prevent the execution of rogue code on their servers, Github allows only a very limited set of Jekyll plugins to be used as part of websites &lt;strong&gt;generated&lt;/strong&gt; directly on the github pages. Read this well: &amp;ldquo;generated on github&amp;rdquo;. That means that if you don&amp;rsquo;t generate your site locally, github will not generate your site if you need custom plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you can still use your own plugins if you want, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to generate your site on your local machine, and push only the result of that to your website&amp;rsquo;s Github pages repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re still puzzled, there are also some &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.sorryapp.com/blogging-with-jekyll/2014/01/31/using-jekyll-plugins-on-github-pages.html&quot;&gt;handy guides for you to read&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve done for my own setup, and that allowed me to write my own little plugins including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &amp;ldquo;301 redirect generator&amp;rdquo; that creates a file pre formatted with all you need to migrate a Wordpress install: drop the result in a .htaccess of an Apache install and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &amp;ldquo;comments mapping plugin&amp;rdquo; that takes a comments json file (generated from a Wordpress WXR file), and attaches them to the correct posts as an array to use in post generation templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &amp;ldquo;categories page generator&amp;rdquo;: based on the categories of each post (as written in their &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/&quot;&gt;YAML Front Matter&lt;/a&gt;), categories will be available under /categories/[cat_name], including pagination options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &amp;ldquo;categories list generator&amp;rdquo; to generate an unordered list to display on your templates pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a set of helpers to automatically generate CDN urls for posts attachments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;On top of this I&amp;rsquo;ve added an RSS feed and a site map generator based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulstamatiou.com/how-to-Wordpress-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Paul&amp;rsquo;s work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deployment-wise, I wanted to use one common structure for two websites: this web orientated website, and another one dedicated to my triathlon passion. That means two static websites hosted on Github, but only one main repository that contains all the posts and jekyll source code, posts and specific configuration for each site being separated on their own git branches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I now have three repositories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one main repository for the core Jekyll stuff and all the plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one repository for the static files of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ekynoxe.com&quot;&gt;web-development / professional website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one repository for the static files of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://tri.ekynoxe.com&quot;&gt;triathlon ramblings website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very simple: the last two are being fed the result of &amp;ldquo;jekyll build&amp;rdquo; from within the main repository.
As I am using rake tasks to simplify my life around Jekyll, all I have to do to publish a post on one or the other is switch to the correct content branch, write, commit, and execute &amp;ldquo;rake generate&amp;rdquo;. Everything else is taken care of automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.sorryapp.com/blogging-with-jekyll/2014/01/31/using-jekyll-plugins-on-github-pages.html&quot;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; to mimic this setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve set-up your own website in a similar way, at this point, you should have something working well. However, if you&amp;rsquo;re hosting a blog, there&amp;rsquo;s one thing you may miss: comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very contentious issue.
As Jekyll will generate a static website, it means once online, there will be nothing that can respond to a form POST on your server. That means no &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; comments. I mean &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; in the technological, HTTP way here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only solutions you have so far are third party commenting systems like &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://moot.it/&quot;&gt;Moot.it&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.livefyre.com/&quot;&gt;Livefyre&lt;/a&gt; or others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried them, each to a certain degree of completeness, but Moot and Livefyre didn&amp;rsquo;t correspond to my needs, and after trying to import my comments from Wordpress into Disqus, having a debate with myself about leaving &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; content (comments on &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; content) with a third party, and reading numerous horror stories about transfers going wrong, I decided to NOT use Disqus in the end. In fact I decided to not use any third party comment system at all. I&amp;rsquo;ve deleted my Disqus account, and I transferred all my old comments to this new site, and I&amp;rsquo;ll build my own commenting system in the future, hopefully with spam control, and as one that should be available open source for self hosting so you can use it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Things I haven&amp;rsquo;t done yet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search: I&amp;rsquo;ll add a site search at some point. Unlike Tim&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://nefariousdesigns.co.uk/&quot;&gt;fantastic web resources site&lt;/a&gt;, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the same link juice and my posts don&amp;rsquo;t appear on many search engines yet. So a little site search could help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polish the publication process, especially around drafts and image uploads. At the moment, it&amp;rsquo;s quite an intensive manual process to create and upload images and galleries. Especially for my triathlon site where I sometimes have 40 photos attached to a post, all with their thumbnail versions. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll come around to do a little plugin to help with image resizing, gallery generation, and upload to S3 / Cloudfront during the publication process through an extension to my Rake tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Not for everyone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a nerd publishing platform. There is a lot to set up initially, and despite the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;best efforts of some&lt;/a&gt;, there are no &amp;ldquo;Jekyll for dummies&amp;rdquo; guides. You must know your way around code, around ruby, around your terminal and around git and Github. At a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But none of this is an issue for me: I&amp;rsquo;m a nerd, and I love it! It&amp;rsquo;s small, and I&amp;rsquo;m in control of everything locally, on my computer. The plugins I now use are pretty much all self-built, and the only thing that could go wrong in the future is my ruby version clashing with an old Jekyll install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than this, the site generated is static, so there&amp;rsquo;s really nothing wrong in that!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/on-jekyll</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/on-jekyll</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>10 years!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In a few months, ekynoxe will celebrate 10 years on the web! There won&amp;rsquo;t be that many celebrations, but for me, it is a great marker to show that I keep doing what I do best, and what I enjoy the most professionally: websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 10 years, ekynoxe went through several changes, both in function and in design, and it is now my professional showcase and point of contact for prospective clients. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it got here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;identity evolution&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/logo_evolution.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/logo_evolution_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;identity evolution&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;The name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked this question many times. Why &amp;ldquo;ekynoxe&amp;rdquo;? And why the strange spelling?
I&amp;rsquo;ll clear the spelling one straight away since it&amp;rsquo;s the easier: there&amp;rsquo;s no special reason. The spelling &amp;ldquo;ekynoxe&amp;rdquo; is my take on the otherwise well known solar event, the equinox. I just needed it to be different, but very close or identical in pronunciation to the correct spelling. In French: &amp;ldquo;equinoxe&amp;rdquo; is pronounced the exact same way that you would pronounce &amp;ldquo;ekynoxe&amp;rdquo;, with a hard K and no &amp;ldquo;w&amp;rdquo; sound after it. It obviously gets lost in translation, but that spelling stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the meaty part: There are several elements into relating to the equinox in the first place, and although it wasn&amp;rsquo;t initially visible at all in the first identity, I kept evolving this as an integral part of the &amp;ldquo;brand&amp;rdquo; since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First what is an equinox? It is &amp;ldquo;the time or date (twice each year) at which the sun crosses the celestial equator, when day and night are of equal length (about 22 September and 20 March).&amp;rdquo; (Oxford dictionary)
The link between me and these dates is simple: my name day in France is on September 21st, start of autumn, and often the autumnal equinox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The early years&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2004, I was in Wales with some friends for a computer course with our French university. As proper geeks, all my friends and I were starting to dab into websites, and wanted to create an identity for ourselves. At the time, it was a way to be personal amongst our group, and a way to be independent of pretty much any online service, as having our own domain name allowed to setup our own web and email servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when I had a first taste of what the initial steps of creating a website are. Like many to this day, I quickly found an idea for the identity, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a real clue about content. What should I display online?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much has happened since then, but the name stuck. It was July 2004 and &amp;ldquo;ekynoxe&amp;rdquo; was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning, the logo didn&amp;rsquo;t show much of the underlying meaning that ekynoxe had for me. It was only a photoshop doodle that I liked. However, I did have a go with the favicon to played around with a representation of this special date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These early attempts came out as crude pixelated icons and small images. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;ve done the first ones in paint, but that&amp;rsquo;s what I could do at the time with limited tools and knowledge about graphics software I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/eky1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a crescent gobbling the sun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The intention there was to have both elements of day and night included, with a moon crescent and rays more usually associated with the sun, or for the second iteration, the moon crescent looking like it was going to gobble up the sun. At the time I was incredibly proud that this little image was me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, the website was a simple photo gallery. I had coded it all by hand in notepad, and I was very proud of it! But aside from a few pretty photos I use to make back then, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much on it. Oh! And it was dark. A fully black background, with only a touch of colour coming from the photos themselves. It was intentional, but in retrospect: a little bit depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;first website!&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v1.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v1_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;first website!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This first version lived on for quite a few years, and it&amp;rsquo;s only in 2007 that I started changing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Refinement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 2005, I greatly improved my illustrator and photoshop skills, and I tried a few more logo options. I had had a though about it, and I now wanted to try and present exactly which equinox I was talking about in the identity: the autumnal one. The following came out and was briefly used in a few sites, including on some of my first clients' for a reference back to my studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/eky2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;second logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The new version of the website was still dark, but the actual definition of the logo was getting closer to the origin of the name: dark and light together, or more &amp;ldquo;sunshine and night&amp;rdquo;.  Simply put, the idea was to represent the night taking over the day, hence the black elements reaching for the sun to pull it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;site version 2, never published&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v2.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v2_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;site version 2, never published&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That version was never published, though, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a drive or the time to fully work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Contenders?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of this logo and the &amp;ldquo;arms&amp;rdquo; around a central disc is a bit far fetched (and still is, just read on&amp;hellip;), but interestingly, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only one thinking about it. There was a website in France with a very similar name: ekinoxe (with an &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;) that had a logo very close in idea to this version.
The similarities don&amp;rsquo;t stop there as their domain name was registered less than a month after mine, back in 2004, and it was also the site of a web development company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/ekinoxe_fr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ekinoxe.fr contenders?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I still find it amusing that we never got in touch an I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about them until late 2011, just before they went into administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Abstraction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous website lived for around 4 years, but as I sharpened my development and design skills, my personal preference went for simple, clean and minimalistic designs. I then had another go at modifying my identity to reflect this, and going all light in colour, and much more polished.
The sun was still there, the &amp;ldquo;night reaching out&amp;rdquo; too, but in a much simpler form, and in a symmetric way this time. This brought better balance to the logo itself and the identity, while making it a bit more professional and polished. I also took the opportunity to invert the theme and go light in colours rather than full black. It was very much the &amp;ldquo;aqua&amp;rdquo; years where everything on the web had to have what we now think as a horrible &amp;ldquo;water bubble&amp;rdquo; effect and gradients everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/eky3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;third logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This was the ekynoxe identity for many years and was still on some of my error pages for several of my websites until I recently decided to redesign them all completely. You may well still find it around on some web caches!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;published site version 3&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v3.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v3_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;published site version 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s interesting, and what attracted me in the equinoxe is that it talks about balance, equilibrium, and without being too pompous, some kind of perfection. Thinking along these lines lead to the le latest instalment of my identity which I have just published&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Minimalism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months back I decided to take a leap and get rid of the heavy and cumbersome CMS that Wordpress has become for my needs. I removed the style on my portfolio site, and stopped caring about how my blog looked like, so I could focus on redesigning them at the same time. Given that I was going to start from scratch with all of them rather than try and transfer themes and outdated styles, having a clean slate on all fronts was the perfect thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took some time, but only because I wanted both style and platform to work well for me, and for what I publish. Platform wise I went with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, and that will be the subject of other, more technical, posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the design, my ideas are now definitely more minimalistic designs rather than overcharged colourful patchworks, and I decided to incorporate this into my identity too. That would convey a sense of cleanliness with no over-complication of things which I try to apply to my business.
I realised that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need the &amp;lsquo;night reaching out for the sun&amp;rsquo; anymore. The circle alone would be enough. But I still kept the balance in the logo with the use of the circle shape itself. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot more subtle, but in the end it&amp;rsquo;s quite simple, really:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balance&lt;/strong&gt;: the area covered by the circle is the same than the contained disc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autumn&lt;/strong&gt;: the default logo on a white background is a dark circle, the night, around a white disc: the day being absorbed by the night. On any other background with enough contrast, it&amp;rsquo;s a white circle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/eky4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fourth logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;a bit of mathematics&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/logo_maths.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/logo_maths_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;a bit of mathematics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The simple mathematics above helped to get the correct shape: get one of the radius, and you can build the rest. The area of the inner disc is the same than the thick circle around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me that is the balance of things. A circle is a perfect shape, and it should work pretty much anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have now completed only one part of all the redesigns I want to do. I started by merging and redesigning my blog and portfolio (on this site), and moving all triathlon related blog posts to their own website (now on &lt;a href=&quot;http://tri.ekynoxe.com&quot;&gt;http://tri.ekynoxe.com&lt;/a&gt;). But there is still a lot of work todo: I still have to bring back old work items to the portfolio area of this site, and present them in a more detailed way than they&amp;rsquo;ve ever been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;version 4&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v4.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v4_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;version 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then there will be redesigning my triathlon pages with a design on the same base, but overall more sporty, than this portfolio. And finally there will be my little personal site that I host at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathieudavy.com&quot;&gt;http://www.mathieudavy.com&lt;/a&gt; which is in urgent need of attention!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 11:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/10-years</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/10-years</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Closing the Hammersmith Barrier website</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2011, I got fed up with the Hammersmith council and TFL not rising up to take ownership of the Hammersmith bridge barriers being constantly broken.
I was cycling to work through the bridge every day, and most of the time, the bus lane barriers would be broken, on the side of the road, if not dangling from their support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-09-closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website/original.png&quot; title=&quot;One of the many days the south barrier was broken&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140209]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-09-closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website/original_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;One of the many days the south barrier was broken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It led all sorts of traffic go through the bridge, including some that should not have gone there like vans and small trucks.
As a cyclist, this was dangerous, and I thought that with a record of the sate of the barrier everyday through the week, it would highlight the lack of attention that this road feature was receiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not only for cycling safety, but to preserve the bridge from being crammed with vehicles too big, and it was failing this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the little website that I created, I reported every time I went through there, most of the time with photographic evidence, the state of both north and south barriers, and the statistics very shocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 7 months the website had been up, the south barrier was broken for more than 70% of the time, while the north one was out of action 20% of the time. But because the roads (or bus lanes) are part of the TFL network, they were spending the minimum amount of money on it, while the council didn&amp;rsquo;t want to hear about the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an interesting experiment in capturing everyday waste of public money, time and effort, for a solution that could have been converted to rising bollards or another, less likely to break piece of traffic management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I changed jobs and I&amp;rsquo;m no longer cycling through the Hammersmith bridge, so I can&amp;rsquo;t record the status of those barriers any-more. I&amp;rsquo;ve therefore decided to close the site for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for those who knew about it and had a little interest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-09-closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website/hammersmith_barrier.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The Hammersmith barrier website&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140209]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-09-closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website/hammersmith_barrier_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Hammersmith barrier website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Below is what the site description read when it was up and running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hammersmith bridge bus lanes feature barriers to prevent HGVs and other heavy vehicles to access the bridge, as it&amp;rsquo;s not been designed to withstand the weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, these barriers are broken, out of order, or removed regularly, sometimes posing serious risks to passers by. &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/37791955&quot; title=&quot;the barrier strikes back&quot;&gt;The barrier strikes back&lt;/a&gt; shows this, where the barrier falls in front of 3 cyclists that were going through the lane. Dangling from a cable inside the tube, the barrier was simply swinging one side to the other, and pedestrians could have been injured as well.
Fairly recent articles on &lt;a href=&quot;http://focustransport2011.blogspot.co.uk/2011/11/calls-to-tackle-bus-drivers-over-bridge.html&quot; title=&quot;Focus transport on the Hammersmith barrier&quot;&gt;Focus transport&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-15843353&quot; title=&quot;BBC article&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getwestlondon.co.uk/news/local-news/bus-drivers-caught-tearing-down-5982157&quot; title=&quot;Fulham and Hammersmith news: Bus drivers caught tearing down Hammersmith bridge safety barrier&quot;&gt;Fulham and Hammersmith Chronicle (now the Get West London website)&lt;/a&gt; have shown that bus drivers themselves sometimes remove the barriers so they can go over the bridge. They claim it&amp;rsquo;s because the barriers don&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rationale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By recording the status of the bus lane barriers when I pass them (it&amp;rsquo;s on my daily commute), I want to have a demonstration of their uselessness, and I want to present this as wastage of public money towards the constant repairs of the barriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can argue that the cyclists mentioned above should not have been in the lane, but frankly, I&amp;rsquo;d question first the design of the cycle route leading the the South access to the bridge. &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/35142018&quot; title=&quot;Misleading road markings&quot;&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; Shows the markings indicating cyclists to get on the &amp;ldquo;shared pavement&amp;rdquo;, for the only purpose to go around the barrier. Doing this is dangerous for both cyclists and pedestrians and could be avoided very easily! A study by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.richmondlcc.co.uk/2010/11/08/another-veloteer-review-hammersmith-bridge/&quot; title=&quot;Richmond Cycling Campaign: Another veloteer review Hammersmith bridge&quot;&gt;Richmond Cycling campaign&lt;/a&gt; has shown this for a long time now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solutions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the cycle lane design issue, simply shortening the barrier by a foot or two would allow cyclists to pass by (when the barrier works, obviously) while still preventing large vehicles to go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solution to the barrier itself would be to use rising bollards instead of a barrier. Maybe there would be a higher upfront cost, but that would be offset by not spending money on constant repairs. They certainly seem to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PRCA8MvedIo&quot; title=&quot;Another solution&quot;&gt;work well in Manchester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That would also fix the cycle lane layout, by allowing cyclist to pass between the bollards, and not have to go on the &amp;ldquo;shared&amp;rdquo; pavement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ellen now ready for home visits</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My amazing other half is now taking bookings for home physio visits should you need it.
Please help spread the word!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/&quot; href=&quot;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-01-06-ellen-now-ready-for-home-visits/ellen_physio.png&quot; alt=&quot;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Thanks on her behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/ellen-now-ready-for-home-visits</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/ellen-now-ready-for-home-visits</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Browsers</title>
                <description>&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-16-browsers/browsers.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Browsers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/browsers</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/browsers</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Solex 3800: Something to restore and cherish</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, I inherited my mum&amp;#8217;s speed machine! A 1967 VeloSolex that has spent the best part of the last 30 years in a dark garage on the Normandy peninsula coast in France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/3800.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Solex 3800&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/3800_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Solex 3800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;#8217;s to start and make this wonderful little machine alive again soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='gallery'&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/3800.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Solex 3800&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/3800_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Solex 3800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2830.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Engine number&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2830_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Engine number&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2831.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Engine info&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2831_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Engine info&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2832.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Engine type&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2832_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Engine type&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2834.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Original invoice&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2834_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Original invoice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Realm Game: a fantastic looking project to back on kickstarter</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A fantastic looking project &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/995134339/the-realm-game&quot; title=&quot;The Realm Game on Kickstarter&quot;&gt;to back on Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; from former colleague Tom Szirtes and the crew at Atomhawk! Get pledging now, they need your support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;An emotive visually stunning game set in a familiar but strange future &amp;#8211; an imaginative evolution of the point&amp;amp;click adventure genre&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/995134339/the-realm-game&quot; title=&quot;Realm, the game&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-05-09-the-realm-game-a-fantastic-looking-project-to-back-on-kickstarter/realm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Realm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/the-realm-game-a-fantastic-looking-project-to-back-on-kickstarter</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/the-realm-game-a-fantastic-looking-project-to-back-on-kickstarter</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Instants Tisss, my sister&amp;#8217;s business, has now launched!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Several months in the making to sort out all the details and go around the inevitable changes of mind that my sister always goes through, her business online store, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instantstisses.com/&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tisss&quot;&gt;Instants Tisss&lt;/a&gt;,is now open!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instantstisses.com/&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tisss&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-03-03-instants-tisses-my-sisters-business-has-now-launched/logo_IT.png&quot; alt=&quot;Instants Tisss&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Instants Tisss&amp;#8221; is French for &amp;#8220;Woven instants&amp;#8221;, and her business is all about special occasion cards and paper supports with a twist: fabric! Marrying high quality printed paper and light fabrics should bring an extra personal touch to your special occasions. At the moment she has an extensive collection of &lt;a href=&quot;https://instants-tisses.myshopify.com/collections/mariage-pacs&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tisss wedding section&quot;&gt;wedding&lt;/a&gt; invitations, menus, dinner table plans and cards, but a &lt;a href=&quot;https://instants-tisses.myshopify.com/collections/naissance&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tisss birth section&quot;&gt;birth&lt;/a&gt; section is coming as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you don&amp;#8217;t find anything that really tickles your fancy in the large existing collection, there is also a &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instantstisses.com/pages/sur-mesure&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tisss custom section&quot;&gt;custom&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; service that should let you get a quote on your ideal, personalised support for your special occasions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do pay her store a visit, use google translate if you don&amp;#8217;t understand French, and do buy some of her stuff! She&amp;#8217;s getting started and needs all the support she can get!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the techies of you who read this, her site has been done using the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://shopify.com&quot; title=&quot;Shopify&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;with a completely custom theme.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/instants-tisses-my-sisters-business-has-now-launched</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/instants-tisses-my-sisters-business-has-now-launched</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>