<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ekynoxe - Web development in London</title>
        <description>Mathieu Davy's one man web studio</description>
        <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://ww.ekynoxe.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 21:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 21:38:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>10 years!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In a few months, ekynoxe will celebrate 10 years on the web! There won&amp;rsquo;t be that many celebrations, but for me, it is a great marker to show that I keep doing what I do best, and what I enjoy the most professionally: websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 10 years, ekynoxe went through several changes, both in function and in design, and it is now my professional showcase and point of contact for prospective clients. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it got here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;identity evolution&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/logo_evolution.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/logo_evolution_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;identity evolution&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;The name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked this question many times. Why &amp;ldquo;ekynoxe&amp;rdquo;? And why the strange spelling?
I&amp;rsquo;ll clear the spelling one straight away since it&amp;rsquo;s the easier: there&amp;rsquo;s no special reason. The spelling &amp;ldquo;ekynoxe&amp;rdquo; is my take on the otherwise well known solar event, the equinox. I just needed it to be different, but very close or identical in pronunciation to the correct spelling. In French: &amp;ldquo;equinoxe&amp;rdquo; is pronounced the exact same way that you would pronounce &amp;ldquo;ekynoxe&amp;rdquo;, with a hard K and no &amp;ldquo;w&amp;rdquo; sound after it. It obviously gets lost in translation, but that spelling stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the meaty part: There are several elements into relating to the equinox in the first place, and although it wasn&amp;rsquo;t initially visible at all in the first identity, I kept evolving this as an integral part of the &amp;ldquo;brand&amp;rdquo; since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First what is an equinox? It is &amp;ldquo;the time or date (twice each year) at which the sun crosses the celestial equator, when day and night are of equal length (about 22 September and 20 March).&amp;rdquo; (Oxford dictionary)
The link between me and these dates is simple: my name day in France is on September 21st, start of autumn, and often the autumnal equinox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The early years&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2004, I was in Wales with some friends for a computer course with our French university. As proper geeks, all my friends and I were starting to dab into websites, and wanted to create an identity for ourselves. At the time, it was a way to be personal amongst our group, and a way to be independent of pretty much any online service, as having our own domain name allowed to setup our own web and email servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when I had a first taste of what the initial steps of creating a website are. Like many to this day, I quickly found an idea for the identity, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a real clue about content. What should I display online?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much has happened since then, but the name stuck. It was July 2004 and &amp;ldquo;ekynoxe&amp;rdquo; was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning, the logo didn&amp;rsquo;t show much of the underlying meaning that ekynoxe had for me. It was only a photoshop doodle that I liked. However, I did have a go with the favicon to played around with a representation of this special date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These early attempts came out as crude pixelated icons and small images. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;ve done the first ones in paint, but that&amp;rsquo;s what I could do at the time with limited tools and knowledge about graphics software I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/eky1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a crescent gobbling the sun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The intention there was to have both elements of day and night included, with a moon crescent and rays more usually associated with the sun, or for the second iteration, the moon crescent looking like it was going to gobble up the sun. At the time I was incredibly proud that this little image was me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, the website was a simple photo gallery. I had coded it all by hand in notepad, and I was very proud of it! But aside from a few pretty photos I use to make back then, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much on it. Oh! And it was dark. A fully black background, with only a touch of colour coming from the photos themselves. It was intentional, but in retrospect: a little bit depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;first website!&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v1.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v1_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;first website!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This first version lived on for quite a few years, and it&amp;rsquo;s only in 2007 that I started changing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Refinement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 2005, I greatly improved my illustrator and photoshop skills, and I tried a few more logo options. I had had a though about it, and I now wanted to try and present exactly which equinox I was talking about in the identity: the autumnal one. The following came out and was briefly used in a few sites, including on some of my first clients' for a reference back to my studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/eky2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;second logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The new version of the website was still dark, but the actual definition of the logo was getting closer to the origin of the name: dark and light together, or more &amp;ldquo;sunshine and night&amp;rdquo;.  Simply put, the idea was to represent the night taking over the day, hence the black elements reaching for the sun to pull it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;site version 2, never published&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v2.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v2_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;site version 2, never published&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That version was never published, though, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a drive or the time to fully work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Contenders?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of this logo and the &amp;ldquo;arms&amp;rdquo; around a central disc is a bit far fetched (and still is, just read on&amp;hellip;), but interestingly, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only one thinking about it. There was a website in France with a very similar name: ekinoxe (with an &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;) that had a logo very close in idea to this version.
The similarities don&amp;rsquo;t stop there as their domain name was registered less than a month after mine, back in 2004, and it was also the site of a web development company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/ekinoxe_fr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ekinoxe.fr contenders?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I still find it amusing that we never got in touch an I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about them until late 2011, just before they went into administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Abstraction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous website lived for around 4 years, but as I sharpened my development and design skills, my personal preference went for simple, clean and minimalistic designs. I then had another go at modifying my identity to reflect this, and going all light in colour, and much more polished.
The sun was still there, the &amp;ldquo;night reaching out&amp;rdquo; too, but in a much simpler form, and in a symmetric way this time. This brought better balance to the logo itself and the identity, while making it a bit more professional and polished. I also took the opportunity to invert the theme and go light in colours rather than full black. It was very much the &amp;ldquo;aqua&amp;rdquo; years where everything on the web had to have what we now think as a horrible &amp;ldquo;water bubble&amp;rdquo; effect and gradients everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/eky3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;third logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This was the ekynoxe identity for many years and was still on some of my error pages for several of my websites until I recently decided to redesign them all completely. You may well still find it around on some web caches!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;published site version 3&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v3.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v3_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;published site version 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s interesting, and what attracted me in the equinoxe is that it talks about balance, equilibrium, and without being too pompous, some kind of perfection. Thinking along these lines lead to the le latest instalment of my identity which I have just published&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Minimalism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months back I decided to take a leap and get rid of the heavy and cumbersome CMS that Wordpress has become for my needs. I removed the style on my portfolio site, and stopped caring about how my blog looked like, so I could focus on redesigning them at the same time. Given that I was going to start from scratch with all of them rather than try and transfer themes and outdated styles, having a clean slate on all fronts was the perfect thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took some time, but only because I wanted both style and platform to work well for me, and for what I publish. Platform wise I went with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, and that will be the subject of other, more technical, posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the design, my ideas are now definitely more minimalistic designs rather than overcharged colourful patchworks, and I decided to incorporate this into my identity too. That would convey a sense of cleanliness with no over-complication of things which I try to apply to my business.
I realised that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need the &amp;lsquo;night reaching out for the sun&amp;rsquo; anymore. The circle alone would be enough. But I still kept the balance in the logo with the use of the circle shape itself. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot more subtle, but in the end it&amp;rsquo;s quite simple, really:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balance&lt;/strong&gt;: the area covered by the circle is the same than the contained disc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autumn&lt;/strong&gt;: the default logo on a white background is a dark circle, the night, around a white disc: the day being absorbed by the night. On any other background with enough contrast, it&amp;rsquo;s a white circle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/eky4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fourth logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;a bit of mathematics&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/logo_maths.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/logo_maths_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;a bit of mathematics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The simple mathematics above helped to get the correct shape: get one of the radius, and you can build the rest. The area of the inner disc is the same than the thick circle around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me that is the balance of things. A circle is a perfect shape, and it should work pretty much anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have now completed only one part of all the redesigns I want to do. I started by merging and redesigning my blog and portfolio (on this site), and moving all triathlon related blog posts to their own website (now on &lt;a href=&quot;http://tri.ekynoxe.com&quot;&gt;http://tri.ekynoxe.com&lt;/a&gt;). But there is still a lot of work todo: I still have to bring back old work items to the portfolio area of this site, and present them in a more detailed way than they&amp;rsquo;ve ever been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;version 4&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v4.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-10-years/v4_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;version 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then there will be redesigning my triathlon pages with a design on the same base, but overall more sporty, than this portfolio. And finally there will be my little personal site that I host at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathieudavy.com&quot;&gt;http://www.mathieudavy.com&lt;/a&gt; which is in urgent need of attention!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 11:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/10-years</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/10-years</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Closing the Hammersmith Barrier website</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2011, I got fed up with the Hammersmith council and TFL not rising up to take ownership of the Hammersmith bridge barriers being constantly broken.
I was cycling to work through the bridge every day, and most of the time, the bus lane barriers would be broken, on the side of the road, if not dangling from their support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-09-closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website/original.png&quot; title=&quot;One of the many days the south barrier was broken&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140209]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-09-closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website/original_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;One of the many days the south barrier was broken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It led all sorts of traffic go through the bridge, including some that should not have gone there like vans and small trucks.
As a cyclist, this was dangerous, and I thought that with a record of the sate of the barrier everyday through the week, it would highlight the lack of attention that this road feature was receiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not only for cycling safety, but to preserve the bridge from being crammed with vehicles too big, and it was failing this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the little website that I created, I reported every time I went through there, most of the time with photographic evidence, the state of both north and south barriers, and the statistics very shocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 7 months the website had been up, the south barrier was broken for more than 70% of the time, while the north one was out of action 20% of the time. But because the roads (or bus lanes) are part of the TFL network, they were spending the minimum amount of money on it, while the council didn&amp;rsquo;t want to hear about the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an interesting experiment in capturing everyday waste of public money, time and effort, for a solution that could have been converted to rising bollards or another, less likely to break piece of traffic management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I changed jobs and I&amp;rsquo;m no longer cycling through the Hammersmith bridge, so I can&amp;rsquo;t record the status of those barriers any-more. I&amp;rsquo;ve therefore decided to close the site for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for those who knew about it and had a little interest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-09-closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website/hammersmith_barrier.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The Hammersmith barrier website&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140209]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-09-closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website/hammersmith_barrier_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Hammersmith barrier website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Below is what the site description read when it was up and running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hammersmith bridge bus lanes feature barriers to prevent HGVs and other heavy vehicles to access the bridge, as it&amp;rsquo;s not been designed to withstand the weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, these barriers are broken, out of order, or removed regularly, sometimes posing serious risks to passers by. &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/37791955&quot; title=&quot;the barrier strikes back&quot;&gt;The barrier strikes back&lt;/a&gt; shows this, where the barrier falls in front of 3 cyclists that were going through the lane. Dangling from a cable inside the tube, the barrier was simply swinging one side to the other, and pedestrians could have been injured as well.
Fairly recent articles on &lt;a href=&quot;http://focustransport2011.blogspot.co.uk/2011/11/calls-to-tackle-bus-drivers-over-bridge.html&quot; title=&quot;Focus transport on the Hammersmith barrier&quot;&gt;Focus transport&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-15843353&quot; title=&quot;BBC article&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getwestlondon.co.uk/news/local-news/bus-drivers-caught-tearing-down-5982157&quot; title=&quot;Fulham and Hammersmith news: Bus drivers caught tearing down Hammersmith bridge safety barrier&quot;&gt;Fulham and Hammersmith Chronicle (now the Get West London website)&lt;/a&gt; have shown that bus drivers themselves sometimes remove the barriers so they can go over the bridge. They claim it&amp;rsquo;s because the barriers don&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rationale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By recording the status of the bus lane barriers when I pass them (it&amp;rsquo;s on my daily commute), I want to have a demonstration of their uselessness, and I want to present this as wastage of public money towards the constant repairs of the barriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can argue that the cyclists mentioned above should not have been in the lane, but frankly, I&amp;rsquo;d question first the design of the cycle route leading the the South access to the bridge. &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/35142018&quot; title=&quot;Misleading road markings&quot;&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; Shows the markings indicating cyclists to get on the &amp;ldquo;shared pavement&amp;rdquo;, for the only purpose to go around the barrier. Doing this is dangerous for both cyclists and pedestrians and could be avoided very easily! A study by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.richmondlcc.co.uk/2010/11/08/another-veloteer-review-hammersmith-bridge/&quot; title=&quot;Richmond Cycling Campaign: Another veloteer review Hammersmith bridge&quot;&gt;Richmond Cycling campaign&lt;/a&gt; has shown this for a long time now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solutions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the cycle lane design issue, simply shortening the barrier by a foot or two would allow cyclists to pass by (when the barrier works, obviously) while still preventing large vehicles to go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solution to the barrier itself would be to use rising bollards instead of a barrier. Maybe there would be a higher upfront cost, but that would be offset by not spending money on constant repairs. They certainly seem to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PRCA8MvedIo&quot; title=&quot;Another solution&quot;&gt;work well in Manchester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That would also fix the cycle lane layout, by allowing cyclist to pass between the bollards, and not have to go on the &amp;ldquo;shared&amp;rdquo; pavement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/closing-the-hammersmith-barrier-website</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ellen now ready for home visits</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My amazing other half is now taking bookings for home physio visits should you need it.
Please help spread the word!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/&quot; href=&quot;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-01-06-ellen-now-ready-for-home-visits/ellen_physio.png&quot; alt=&quot;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Thanks on her behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/ellen-now-ready-for-home-visits</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/ellen-now-ready-for-home-visits</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Browsers</title>
                <description>&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-16-browsers/browsers.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Browsers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/browsers</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/browsers</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Solex 3800: Something to restore and cherish</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, I inherited my mum&amp;#8217;s speed machine! A 1967 VeloSolex that has spent the best part of the last 30 years in a dark garage on the Normandy peninsula coast in France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/3800.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Solex 3800&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/3800_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Solex 3800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;#8217;s to start and make this wonderful little machine alive again soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='gallery'&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/3800.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Solex 3800&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/3800_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Solex 3800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2830.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Engine number&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2830_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Engine number&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2831.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Engine info&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2831_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Engine info&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2832.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Engine type&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2832_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Engine type&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2834.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Original invoice&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6255]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-06-09-solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish/IMG_2834_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Original invoice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/solex-3800-something-to-restore-and-cherish</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Realm Game: a fantastic looking project to back on kickstarter</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A fantastic looking project &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/995134339/the-realm-game&quot; title=&quot;The Realm Game on Kickstarter&quot;&gt;to back on Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; from former colleague Tom Szirtes and the crew at Atomhawk! Get pledging now, they need your support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;An emotive visually stunning game set in a familiar but strange future &amp;#8211; an imaginative evolution of the point&amp;amp;click adventure genre&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/995134339/the-realm-game&quot; title=&quot;Realm, the game&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-05-09-the-realm-game-a-fantastic-looking-project-to-back-on-kickstarter/realm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Realm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/the-realm-game-a-fantastic-looking-project-to-back-on-kickstarter</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/the-realm-game-a-fantastic-looking-project-to-back-on-kickstarter</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Instants Tissés, my sister&amp;#8217;s business, has now launched!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Several months in the making to sort out all the details and go around the inevitable changes of mind that my sister always goes through, her business online store, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instantstisses.com/&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tissés&quot;&gt;Instants Tissés&lt;/a&gt;, is now open!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instantstisses.com/&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tissés&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-03-03-instants-tisses-my-sisters-business-has-now-launched/logo_IT.png&quot; alt=&quot;Instants Tissés&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Instants Tissés&amp;#8221; is French for &amp;#8220;Woven instants&amp;#8221;, and her business is all about special occasion cards and paper supports with a twist: fabric! Marrying high quality printed paper and light fabrics should bring an extra personal touch to your special occasions. At the moment she has an extensive collection of &lt;a href=&quot;https://instants-tisses.myshopify.com/collections/mariage-pacs&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tissés wedding section&quot;&gt;wedding&lt;/a&gt; invitations, menus, dinner table plans and cards, but a &lt;a href=&quot;https://instants-tisses.myshopify.com/collections/naissance&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tissés birth section&quot;&gt;birth&lt;/a&gt; section is coming as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you don&amp;#8217;t find anything that really tickles your fancy in the large existing collection, there is also a &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instantstisses.com/pages/sur-mesure&quot; title=&quot;Instants Tissés custom section&quot;&gt;custom&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; service that should let you get a quote on your ideal, personalised support for your special occasions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do pay her store a visit, use google translate if you don&amp;#8217;t understand French, and do buy some of her stuff! She&amp;#8217;s getting started and needs all the support she can get!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the techies of you who read this, her site has been done using the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://shopify.com&quot; title=&quot;Shopify&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt; with a completely custom theme.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/instants-tisses-my-sisters-business-has-now-launched</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/instants-tisses-my-sisters-business-has-now-launched</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ideas for Twickenham city center</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some fantastic ideas for the renewal of Twickenham city center.
Please repost and discuss! I&amp;#8217;m sure there will be plenty of different views, but let&amp;#8217;s all be constructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Love Twickenham, Go Dutch&quot; href=&quot;http://pedestrianiselondon.tumblr.com/post/34477053931/love-twickenham-go-dutch&quot;&gt;http://pedestrianiselondon.tumblr.com/post/34477053931/love-twickenham-go-dutch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pedestrianiselondon.tumblr.com/post/34477053931/love-twickenham-go-dutch&quot; title=&quot;Twickenham&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2012-10-30-ideas-for-twickenham-city-center/twick.png&quot; alt=&quot;Twickenham&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/ideas-for-twickenham-city-center</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/ideas-for-twickenham-city-center</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Should you know TCP/IP to work for a web company?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting discussion (argument?) popped in my tweets yesterday in the form of TCP/IP knowledge depth to be able to work at a web company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2012-09-25-should-you-know-tcpip-to-work-for-a-web-company/tweetshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The tweet that prompted it all&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That quickly prompted quite a few replies from developers and techs leads of different levels and knowledge, including myself, but none of us asked the question: &amp;#8220;for which role?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of different roles at a web company, and if we exclude the obvious non techies ones (I doubt the receptionist gives a damn about MTU and error control), we can still argue about the depth of network knowledge required to occupy a technical role.
Let&amp;#8217;s be clear here: we&amp;#8217;re &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; talking about connecting your laptop to your corporate wifi network, but about network protocols and how they work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The pure front-end developer: &lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;d argue you only need some very small basics, if any, about network protocols to do an awesome job without any problem. I hope you know what an IP address is, and that&amp;#8217;s possibly the only thing you&amp;#8217;ll need. If you don&amp;#8217;t, dig it up, but don&amp;#8217;t learn the whole CCNA syllabus. No need. Knowing HTTP, on the other hand, is not an option these days, even for &amp;#8220;pure front-enders&amp;#8221; who&amp;#8217;ll most likely have to do something with asynchronous javaScript calls at some point or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The all rounder&lt;/strong&gt;: If, like me, you&amp;#8217;re one of those, doing some front end and backend code, you&amp;#8217;ll probably want to know a bit more about what rules data transfers across networks. Having a little knowledge about network protocols, what they generally do and how to ping/trace stuff is a good thing. But I am really not convinced that knowing the inner workings TCP/IP should be a requirement to land you a job. Hands up all rounders who have had to dig in TCP retransmission timeouts or the size of IP datagrams because some packets were being dropped on &amp;#8220;the line&amp;#8221;? Yeah&amp;#8230; I thought so. Probably not many, and the ones who raised their hands either do a networks engineer&amp;#8217;s job, or, like me, did some network studies before falling into development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The back-ender:&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;#8217;s probably a very good asset to have, especially if you work at a web company dealing with large volumes of users, requests, page loads and transactions. Knowing it will probably help a lot in optimisation of data transfers an server communications. I&amp;#8217;d argue here that it is a requirement for you to know where things happen on the network stack. You won&amp;#8217;t need it every day in your job, but you&amp;#8217;ll have an extra weapon in your arsenal in case things get nasty in those lower layers. Having said that, if you don&amp;#8217;t work on networks systems, I&amp;#8217;m pretty sure you can still do an excellent job without the complete knowledge of how IP re-assembles packets or how TCP works out how to retransmis the ones gone astray&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if you&amp;#8217;re interviewing for a network or systems engineer role, then you should not only know what TCP/IP is, but know its inner workings and its quirks. You should know how to trace errors in packets and be able to identify why some retransmission occurs on the networks you&amp;#8217;ll be managing. At this level, basics aren&amp;#8217;t enough anymore, but this is valid in any IT networks department, regardless of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with everything, it&amp;#8217;s all a matter of perspective (and remember I&amp;#8217;m more an all-rounder with a strong preference on front-end development), but I&amp;#8217;d argue you don&amp;#8217;t need a very deep understanding of the inner workings TCP/IP and how it works to &amp;#8220;work at a web company&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt; view?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/should-you-know-tcpip-to-work-for-a-web-company</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/should-you-know-tcpip-to-work-for-a-web-company</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The day one image brought my server down</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;During the viral expansion of the &amp;#8220;Richmond news paper editorial fiasco&amp;#8221;, I submitted &lt;a href=&quot;http://road.cc/content/forum/65843-%E2%80%A6-only-good-cyclist-dead-one-%E2%80%A6%E2%80%9D-%E2%80%93-editor-richmond-magazine-%E2%80%93-september-issue&quot; title=&quot;“… the only good cyclist is a dead one …” – editor of the richmond magazine – september issue&quot;&gt;a post on the road.cc forum&lt;/a&gt;. In it, I had added an image linked straight from my server&amp;#8230; What a great idea! Linking one of the most read cycling forum in the UK to my own domain! Lots of hits! &amp;#8230; yeah, just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2012-09-15-the-day-one-image-brought-my-server-down/one_image_host_down.png&quot; alt=&quot;One image on road.cc...&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I definitely need to do some memory tweaking there, because that single image, requested by the road.cc page views, brought my server to its knees. Not &amp;#8211; good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/the-day-one-image-brought-my-server-down</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/the-day-one-image-brought-my-server-down</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>